William Stadtlander – Computer Engineering

Home: 3261 SW 136th Way, Davie, FL, 33330 | College: 311 Edge Way, Apt. 301, Blacksburg, VA, 24060

Phone: (954) 789-9905 | Email: wastadtlander@vt.edu | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/wastadt

GitHub: www.github.com/wastadtlander | Personal Website: www.wastadt.com

Education

Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Blacksburg, Virginia

<u>GPA: 3.32</u>, Expected Graduation: <u>May 2023</u> Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Experience

Summer Intern, CACI International Inc (Position Accepted for May 2021 – August 2021) Immersive Developer, ISE Department (October 2020 – December 2020)

- Developed a virtual environment as member of an interdisciplinary team focused on providing accessibility to elementary aged students otherwise lacking access
 - Conducted orientation for local public-school educators and administrators

Volunteer Python Developer, *TTCC* (August 2020 – September 2020)

• Part of a volunteer developer team for fan-made revival of Disney's Toontown online, with an average online userbase of 550 players

Technical/Clerical Assistant, Fintz Certified Public Accountants (March 2019 – August 2019)

• File maintenance, per privacy standards, to provide material support to tax filings

Volunteer, Cleveland Clinic Florida (May 2015 – January 2019)

• 300+ hours in Emergency Room, Outpatient and Oncology Pharmacies, Interventional Radiology, Visitor Information

University Involvement

Leadership Team, Student Engineers' Council

- Membership Enrichment Chair (May 2020 Present)
 - Nonprofit organization, supporting and engaging with students in VT COE by organizing the second largest student run career fair and developing vocalizations of their experiences
- Freshman Committee (September 2019 May 2020)
 - Student and community outreach to raise awareness of, and encourage involvement, in College of Engineering
 - Planned, promoted, and managed Engineering Research social, doubling attendance over previous year

Engineering Mentor, CEED (Center for the Enhancement of Engineering) (August 2020 – November 2020)

• Outreach and guidance to a group of six General Engineering freshmen

EPT (Electric Power Train) Member, Formula SAE (September 2019 – October 2020)

• Obtained and advanced skills in circuitry, soldering, and teamwork, to engineer a competitive competition ready open wheel monocoque vehicle

Study Abroad Participant, Rising Sophomore Abroad Program (January 2020 – May 2020)

- Accepted to and studied for student engineering exchange experience to China and then South Africa
- Travel canceled due to Covid-19

Summary

<u>Pursuing internship and co-op opportunities</u>. Currently enrolled in an undergraduate degree program with a major of <u>Computer Engineering</u> and an intended focus on <u>Machine Learning</u>. Pursuing involvement in research and study abroad opportunities, as well as Engineering student government and design teams. Ultimately, would like to achieve advanced degrees and a career including Machine Learning projects that pertain to humanlike neural networks.

Skills

Programing Languages			Computer Engineering	Interpersonal/Industry
Python	Bootstrap	С	SolidWorks	Writing
JavaScript	C++		Circuits	Public Speaking
HTML5	MATLAB		Digital Systems	Team Leadership
CSS	Git		Computational Eng.	MS Office